BEXI CASTILLO

Houston, TX

Phone: 409.504.1214 | Email: bexijoibel@gmail.com

Linkedln: Iinkedin.com/in/bexijoibel GitHub: https://github.com/thechicketarian

Portfolio: https://bexiioibel.com/

SUMMARY

Designer and developer with experience in web design, frontend development, data quality, and client relations. Currently working on a data quality team focused on credit resolutions. Previously worked as a web designer and Client Onboarding Manager on an interdisciplinary team at an eCommerce and Marketing startup. Graduate of University of Texas programming boot-camp and BFA in communication design from Texas State University.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages/Skills: Spanish | HTML, CSS, Javascript, Design Thinking, UI/UX, Responsive Design, jQuery, React, SQL, mySQL, GraphQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, ExpressJS, NodeJS, Git, Bootstrap, State, REST APIs, NPM, Handlebars, Debugging Tools: Adobe Creative Suite, Figma, GitHub, Heroku

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Credit Resolutions Specialist Self, Inc

2021 – Current Austin, TX

Key Accomplishments:

- Contributed to creating a workflow control, testing materials, lead QA testing, and feedback guidelines for newly revamped internal workflows up to date with compliance guidelines.
- Reported findings and data to the control team in order to make the workflows more efficient.
- Complete daily operational reporting tasks and data entry; including eOscars ACDVs, paper dispute
- responses, and customer email communication.
- Monitor internal channels for prioritized workflows in order to efficiently manage deadlines.
- Accurately report data to customer's profiles regarding card/loan operations and disputes.
- Review financial information of clients in order to accurately report data to customers, banks, and credit bureaus.

Web Designer/Client Onboarding Manager SYVO

2019 - 2021 Austin, TX

Key Accomplishments:

- Spearheaded the development of the Client Onboarding department, and collaborated with upper management to create processes and guidelines for new team hires.
- Established a four-member productivity team and delegated operational tasks to three junior client onboarding specialists and secondary supporting product members.
- Lead the management of Spanish speaking customers.
- Created training guidelines and a mentoring program for new hires and off-site support team members.
- Managed deadlines for multiple individual projects and offered support for employees.
- As designer and manager lead the company site launch process. Responsible for taking multiple customers live and transitioning the client from the client onboarding department to account management.
- Responsible for working directly with customers from site kick off to launch, and designed websites and templates for various existing and new clients. Developed online graphics and assets for various websites.

• Collaborated with sales representatives, fellow designers, and developers to manage/design websites from site kick-off/development to launch.

Web Designer/Developer SpaceCraft

2016 - 2019 Austin, TX

Key Accomplishments:

- Responsible for designing websites and templates.
- Responsible for assisting in training new hires.
- Responsible for working directly with customers from site kick off to launch and successfully managed deadlines for multiple projects.
- Collaborated with Sales Representative to project manage and design websites with multiple third-party vendors from site kick-off to launch.
- Responsible for developing furthering brand assets, social media posts, and promotional marketing collateral.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Graphic Designer

ColorMix Graphics & Printing

2016

San Marcos, TX

- Responsible for creating logos and branding for various clients
- Responsible for setting up files correctly with printer specifics in mind
- Designed promotional products such as banners, flyers, cups, t-shirts, business cards, letterheads, vehicle wraps, etc.
- Responsible for production from printing, cutting, and mounting

Graphic Design & Marketing Intern Beanitos, Inc

2016

Austin, TX

- Collaborated with the marketing team on a daily basis
- Responsible for promotional assets such as on pack coupons and event handouts.
- Created on brand promotional stickers
- Designed within brand guidelines and identity
- Lead creative on new flavor exploration and packaging design
- Responsible for photographing on pack photo for new chip flavor

Illustrator 2015-2016

KTSW Radio Texas State University

Responsible for creating compelling and relevant illustrations, for both blog posts and featured articles

EDUCATION

Boot Camp Certificate: *University Of Texas*

Austin, TX 2022

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, ReactJS, and more.

Bachelor of Fine Arts in Communication Design: Texas State University San Marcos, TX 2012-2016